xtranormal.com 2013-06-27

# Storytelling | Xtranormal

**Click here to scroll to the Xtranormal for Education Privacy Statement**

Last updated on Sept 30, 2011.

This privacy statement discloses the privacy practices of Xtranormal Technology Inc. ('Xtranormal') with regard to its web site at[ ](http://www.xtranormal.com/)[www.xtranormal.com](http://www.xtranormal.com/) or other web sites owned or operated by Xtranormal (the 'Site').

Xtranormal recognizes that its customers, visitors, users and others who use the Sites (collectively or individually (the 'Users') value their privacy. This Privacy Policy is incorporated and subject to the Terms of Service. Your use of the Sites and any personal information you provide on the Site remain subject to the terms of this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Service.

NOTE TO KIDS: The Site is not for persons under the age of 13. If you are under 13 years of age, then we encourage you to visit other web sites--there are lots of other nice web sites for you.

Please note that any image, video or other content posted at the direction of Users onto the Site becomes public content and is not considered personally identifiable information subject to this Privacy Policy.

What Information does Xtranormal collect?

Description: You may have to provide 'personally identifiable' information (such as your name, email address, postal mailing address, home/mobile telephone number, credit card number and billing information) when you register as a User and when you participate in certain activities on the Site such as uploading images and captions, uploading videos, positing messages in our forums or in the video comments section, entering contests, taking advantage of promotions, responding to surveys, or subscribing to newsletters or other mailing lists.

Cookies information: When you visit our Site, we may send one or more cookies- small text files containing a string of alphanumeric characters- to your computer that uniquely identifies your browser. Xtranormal uses both session cookies and persistent cookies. A session cookie disappears after you close your browser. A persistent cookie remains after you close your browser and may be used by your browser on subsequent visits to the Site. Persistent cookies may be removed by following your web browser help file direction. You can reset your web browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, some features of the Site may not function properly if the ability to accept cookies is disabled.

Log file information: Log file information is automatically reported by your browser each time you view a web page. When you register with or view the Site, our servers automatically record certain information that your web browser sends whenever you visit any website. This information may include information such as your web request, Internet Protocol ('IP') address, browser language, number of clicks, pages viewed and the order of those pages, the amount of time spent on particular pages, the date and times of your visits to the Site, and one or more cookies that may uniquely identify your browser.

How does Xtranormal uses this information?

If you submit personally identifiable information to us through the Site, then Xtranormal uses the information that we collect to operate, maintain, enhance, and provide to you all of the features and services found on the Site. We will use your email address, without further consent, for administrative or non-marketing purposes such as sending you Account activation, notifying you of major Xtranormal updates, for customer service purposes or to address copyright infringement issues. We use both personally identifiable information and certain non-personally-identifiable information (such as anonymous User usage data, cookies, IP addresses, browser type, click stream data)

Any personal information or content that you voluntarily disclose online becomes publicly available and can be collected and used by others. Your display name (not your email address) may be displayed to other Users when you upload images or videos or send messages through the Site and other users may contact you through messages and comments.

Any images, profiles, videos or other content that you submit to the Site may be redistributed through the Internet and other media, and may be viewed by the general public.

Xtranormal uses 'automatically collected' information to:

  1. Remember your information so that you will not have to re-enter it during your visit or next time you visit the site;
  2. Provide customized third party advertisements, content, and information;
  3. Monitor the effectiveness of third party marketing campaigns;
  4. Monitor aggregate site usage metrics such as total number of visitors and traffic;
  5. Track your entries, submissions, and status in promotions, sweepstakes, and contests; diagnose or fix technology problems reported by our Users or engineers that are associated with the IP addresses controlled by a specific web company or ISP; and
  6. Access your information after you log in.

When does Xtranormal disclose information?

Xtranormal does not share your personally identifiable information with other organizations for their marketing or promotional uses without your express consent.

Xtranormal may disclose personally identifiable information and non-personally-identifiable information to our subsidiaries, affiliated companies or other businesses or persons for the purpose of processing such information on our behalf. We require that they agree to process such information in compliance with our privacy policy, and we use reasonable efforts to limit their use of such information and to use other appropriate confidentiality and security measures.

Xtranormal employs other companies and individuals to perform functions on our behalf such as processing payments and providing customer services. They have access to personal information needed to perform their functions, but may not use it for other purposes.

Xtranormal may disclose 'automatically collected' information and other aggregate non-personally-identifiable information with interested third parties to assist such parties in understanding the usage and demographic patterns for certain programs, content, services, advertisement, promotions, and/or other functionality on the Site.

Xtranormal may disclose personally identifiable information and/or non-personally identifiable information if required to do so by law, or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with applicable laws (such as copyright laws) or respond to a court order, subpoena, or search warrant.

It may be necessary to share information in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding suspected or actual illegal activities, including but not limited to, fraud, potential threats to public safety of any person, violations of our Terms of Service, or as otherwise permitted by law. We may make such disclosures, in some cases, without providing Users notice.

Xtranormal reserves the right to disclose User information that we believe, in good faith, is appropriate or necessary to take precautions against liability; protect Xtranormal from fraudulent, abusive, or unlawful uses; to investigate and defend ourselves against any third party claims or allegations; to assist government enforcement agencies; to protect the security or integrity of the Site; and to protect the rights, property or personal safety of our Users or other persons.

How long does Xtranormal retain personal information?

Xtranormal keeps your information for a period reasonably necessary to meet the purposes for which it was collected or to comply with any legal requirements, including statutory retention periods. When your personal information is no longer required for a specific purpose or legal requirement, it will be erased from our records.

Where is my personal information located?

Your personal information may be stored and processed in servers, including those of our authorized third parties, located in Canada. These servers shall always be subject to the safeguards described in this Privacy Policy to protect against unauthorized collection, use or disclosure, and you shall be able to access the personal information stored in such servers in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

Your choices:

You may, of course, decline to share your personally identifiable information with Xtranormal, in which case, Xtranormal may not be able to provide certain services to you. You may update, correct, or delete your User account information and email preferences at any time by going to the Edit Profile section of the Site; provided however, that upon deletion of your account or profile, please note that some of your personal information, including billing and contact information, may remain in Xtranormal's systems for some limited period of time.

You are responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your unique password and account information at all times.

Please e-mail customer support with any questions or comments about this Privacy Policy.

Third-Party advisers, Links to other Sites:

Xtranormal allows other companies, called third-party ad servers or ad networks, to serve advertisements within the Site. These third party ad servers or ad networks use technology to send, directly through your browser, the advertisements that appear within the Site and they automatically receive your IP address when this happens. Such third party ad servers may also use other technologies (such as cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons) to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and to personalize the advertising content.

Xtranormal does not provide any personally identifiable information to these third-party ad servers or ad networks without your consent or except as part of a specific program or feature for which you will have the ability to opt-in. However, please note that if an advertiser asks Xtranormal to show an advertisement to a certain audience (for example, men ages 18-34) or audience segment (for example, men ages 18-24 who have viewed certain channels of content) and you respond to that advertisement, the advertiser or ad-server may conclude that you fit the description of the audience they are trying to reach.

You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third party ad servers or ad networks. Xtranormal privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of such other advertisers or web sites.

Xtranormal's commitment to data security:

Xtranormal uses commercially reasonable physical, managerial, and technical safeguards to preserve the integrity and security of User information. We cannot, however, ensure or warrant the security of User information you transmit to Xtranormal and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your information, Xtranormal makes commercially reasonable efforts to ensure the security of our systems. However, please note that this is not a guarantee that such information may not be accessed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed by breach of any of our physical, technical, or managerial safeguards.

If Xtranormal learns of a security systems breach, then we may attempt to notify you electronically so that you can take appropriate protective steps. Xtranormal may post a notice on the Site if a security breach occurs. Depending on where you live, you may have a legal right to receive notice of a security breach in writing. To receive a free written notice of a security breach you should e-mail customer support.

Xtranormal's commitment to children's privacy:

Protecting the privacy of young children is especially important. For that reason, Xtranormal does not knowingly collect or maintain personally identifiable information on the Site from persons under 13 years of age, and no part of the Site is directed to persons under 13. If you are under 13 years of age, then please do not use or access the Site at any time or in any manner. If Xtranormal learns that personally-identifiable information of persons less than 13 years of age has been collected on the Site without verifiable parental consent, then Xtranormal will take the appropriate steps to delete the information. If you are a parent or guardian and discover that your child under the age of 13 has obtained an Xtranormal User Account, then you may e-mail customer support and request that Xtranormal delete that child's personal information from its systems.

Questions, comments or accessing or updating your personal information:

If you have any questions or comments about Xtranormal privacy policy, would like to advise us how you would like your personal information not to be used or disclosed, or would like to access or update your personal information, please e-mail customer support. You can also write at Xtranormal Technology Inc. 5555 Avenue Casgrain, Montreal, QC H2T 1Y1 Canada, attention: support. Please note that certain information is required by Xtranormal to process payment and fulfill any orders that you may place through the Site, and if you withdraw your consent to the collection, use or disclosure of your personal information for these purposes, then Xtranormal will not be able to give you the services you wish to obtain.

In the event of Merger, sale or bankruptcy:

If Xtranormal is acquired by or merged with a third party entity, we reserve the right to transfer or assign the information we have collected from the Users as part of such merger, acquisition, sale, or other change of control. In the unlikely event of our bankruptcy, insolvency, reorganization or assignment for the benefit of creditors, or the application of laws or equitable principles affecting creditors' rights generally, we may not be able to control how your personal information is treated, transferred or used.

Acceptance of Privacy Policy:

This Privacy Policy outlines the information usage practices of Xtranormal. By accessing, browsing or using the Site or by submitting your personal information to Xtranormal, you signify your agreement to the terms and conditions of this policy. If you do not agree to this policy, please do not submit your personal information to us. We reserve the right, at our discretion, to change, modify, add or remove portions of this Policy at any time. If at some point in the future there is a material change to our information usage practices that affects your personal information, you will be notified of such change by a conspicuous posting on the Site and will be prompted to elect whether or not you agree to the change. Your acceptance of a revised policy shall mean that you have accepted those changes, subject to your continuing right to notify us at any time as to how you would like us to treat your personal information.

Last modified on: April 24th, 2009.

Contact information:

Please contact Xtranormal with any questions or comments about this Privacy Policy or the Site by emailing customer support

Last updated on Sept 30, 2011.

Our Commitment to Privacy

Xtranormal Technology Inc. is committed to maintaining the security, confidentiality and privacy of your personal information. This is our Privacy Policy. It documents our on-going commitment to you and has been developed in compliance with the The Children's Online Privacy Protection Act, (COPPA).

Scope of Policy

This Policy applies to our collection, use and disclosure of the personal information of children under the age of thirteen (13) using our website and services for Education purposes.

Accountability

We have designated a Privacy Officer who is responsible for our compliance with this Policy. The Privacy Officer may be contacted as described below.

What Do We Collect?

We collect the following types of personal information from all Xtranormal members:

  1. First and Last Name (main Teacher or Administrator only).
  2. Screen name and password
  3. E-mail address (required for Teachers, optional for Students)

Purposes

We collect, use and disclose the data of the student under the age of thirteen (13):

to open the membership account;

to authenticate the identity;

to facilitate communication and sharing with the teacher;

Please note the personal data of a student under thirteen (13) is used for the purpose above, as such Xtranormal will not sell or give your data to third party vendors. Also Xtranormal will not use the contact details of the student under the age of 13 for internal marketing and communications.

You may instruct us to refrain from using or sharing your personal information in any or all of the three ways described above at any time by providing written notification to our Privacy Officer.

Safeguarding Personal Information

We protect the personal information in our custody or control by making reasonable security arrangements to prevent unauthorized access, collection, use, disclosure, copying, modification, disposal or similar risks. We will take reasonable steps, through contractual or other reasonable means, to ensure that the suppliers and agents who assist in providing services to us implement a comparable level of personal information protection. Some specific safeguards may include:

Physical measures such as locked filing cabinets. Organizational measures such as restricting employee access to files and databases as appropriate; Electronic measures such as passwords and firewalls; and

Investigative measures where we have reasonable grounds to believe that personal information is being inappropriately collected used or disclosed. However, absolute privacy cannot be guaranteed for any online animation, private message or other content posted on or shared through Xtranormal, so we strongly recommend that you do not include sensitive personal information in any online content.

Providing Access

You have a right to access your personal information held by us.

Upon written request and authentication of identity, we will provide you your personal information under our control. We will also give you information about the ways in which that information is being used and a description of the individuals and organizations to whom that information has been disclosed. We may charge you a reasonable fee for doing so.

We will make the information available within 30 days of receiving a written request or provide written notice where additional time is required to fulfill the request.

Complaints

We will, on request, provide information regarding our complaint procedure.

Any inquiries, complaints or questions regarding this Policy should be directed in writing to our Privacy Officer as follows:

Privacy Officer  
Xtranormal Technology Inc.  
5555 Avenue Casgrain  
Montreal, QC H2T 1Y1  
Canada  

Changes

We may change this policy from time to time. Please check our website frequently for updates to this.
